# PENGAN ZHOU

Apt.908 10020 103 Ave. NW Edmonton, Alberta T5J 0G8 | 780-901-8823 | pengan1987@msn.com

## **SUMMARY**

PengAn has more than 3 years of working experience in software development and IT services. He is highly skilled and knowledgeable in diverse IT environments, as well as a wide range of software development skills including: network protocols, frameworks and toolsets, industrial computing and mobile technologies.

## **COMPUTER SKILLS**

#### Languages

- · Proficient in: C#, Python, Java, PHP, VB.net, ASP.Net, SQL
- · Familiar with: C/C++, JavaScript, Hibernate, Embedded VB

#### Software

- · Application Frameworks: .Net Framework, .Net Compact Framework, Tapestry, WinForm, Yii Framework
- · Database: MS SQL Server, MySQL, FoxPro, Oracle
- · Environments: Visual Studio, Eclipse, Git
- · Platforms: Microsoft Window, Unix/Linux, Mac OS, Windows CE

## **EXPERIENCE**

## October 2012 to Present

Junior Software Developer, PureInbox Inc. (Edmonton, Alberta, Canada)

- Development and Testing .Net based Digital Video Surveillance System for IP based cameras.
- $\cdot$  Development and Testing Tapestry/Hibernate based telecom expense management system.
- · Development and Testing USB Virtual Serial Port based RFID reader program.
- Development and Testing Front-end for online video processing based PHP, Yii Framework and Python

Technologies used: C#/.Net Framework, PHP/Yii Framework, Python, Java/J2EE, Aforge.net, FFmpeg

## January 2012 to April 2012

Computer Repair Technician, Alberta Computers for Schools (Edmonton, Alberta, Canada)

· Diagnose and troubleshot computer hardware/device driver issues.

- · Deploy Windows Operation System with Windows PE and Windows Deploy Service
- · Make Windows Deploy image use Symantec Ghost

Technologies used: Windows Deployment Service, Windows Networking, Symantec Ghost

## July 2008 to June 2009

- · Mobile Device Support Technician, Jinan BenBird Digital Co. (Jinan, Shandong, China)
- · Deploy and Support Windows Mobile devices.
- Implement Wireless messaging system for Windows Mobile smartphones, Exchange Server and ActiveSync
- · Deploy large scale Wi-Fi coverage with DD-WRT and WDS
- · Development and testing restaurant wireless order system use Windows Mobile PDAs
- · Development and testing localization application for Windows CE devices

Technologies used: Embedded Visual Basic, MS SQL, .Net Compact Framework, Microsoft Exchange Server

## January 2007 to June 2008

- · Network Technician, Jinan Fisher Cyber Café (Jinan, Shandong, China)
- · Maintenance and Manage Windows networks
- · Implement diskless Windows XP workstation with gPXE and iSCSI
- · Computer hardware upgrades and repair
- · Monitoring Cisco routers and layer 3 switches
- $\cdot$  Monitoring Windows Servers with RDP/Citrix ICA remote desktop service

Technologies used: Linux (Cent OS 4), Bash, Windows Server, TCP/IP networking

## **EDUCATION**

June 2012 Diploma Digital Media and IT, Northern Alberta Institute of Technology

July 2009 B.A. Culture Industries Management, Shandong College of Arts